kinto behr

data scientist / data engineer

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data professional with experience working in both modeling and engineering focused roles. No matter which side of the fence I'm on, I love writing clean, modular, well-organised code to solve challenging data problems. I am completely comfortable writing production-ready code in R and Python, and have a good deal of experience designing and maintaining SQL databases.

Outside of work, I am an active contributor to the open source software community, having developed or made large contributions to a number of R packages. I'm also an avid reader, particularly of philosophy, and a keen (though not very good!) rock climber.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Scientist

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am currently shared between the data and statistical methods teams, spending half my time in each. This being the case, I work on a fairly wide variety of things.

On the one hand, I am responsible for carrying out various statistical procedures (e.g. weighting, small area estimation, propensity modelling, forecasting) and writing technical reports.

On the other hand, I am the technical lead on a variety of software engineering projects, typically focussed on data modeling, integration, processing, analysis and reporting, but often general application development. Some of the things I've worked on in this latter capacity are:

- Developing and deploying machine learning models, and designing the API access to them
- Developing a three-tier lottery application for setting up and running prize draws.
- SQL database design and data pipeline architecture for various projects.

Data Engineer

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data engineer on the https://www.qilt.edu.au/surveys/student-experience-survey-(ses)SES, which approaches hundreds of thousands of higher education students each year. In this capacity, I was responsible for maintaining the data infrustructure throughout the full length of the pipeline from sample collection and validation, through fieldwork operations and data processing, to report production.

In addition, I made key contributions to the in-house package architecture and Shiny application suite. In particular, I

- Authored and/or maintained the majority of in-house packages
- Trained other data professionals in package development

• Developed a number of complex Shiny applications which became core to projects across the business, including one which won a company-wide competition

Team Lead

Sidekicker | 2018 - 2020

I was in charge of the community operations team, which was responsible for ensuring that the application marketplace was running smoothly.

Alongside managing 15+ casual staff, I

- · Performed data analysis using SQL and Python
- Automated core processes to save ~100hrs of labour-time per month

EDUCATION

Master of Statistics

University of New South Wales | 2021 - 2023

- Awarded with Excellence
- Thesis title: Classification with Semi-Supervised Learning Algorithms
- WAM: 92%

Bachelor of Arts (Honours)

University of Melbourne | 2019

- Recieved the Hastie Prize for graduating top of my class
- Thesis title: Epistemic Relativism: The Futility of the Argument from the Criterion
- GPA: 4.0 (WAM: 87%)

Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Received numerous academic awards including the Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards for achieving top marks across various physics courses
- Majors (minors): Philosophy (Japanese) and Physics (Mathematics)
- GPA: 3.93 (WAM: 87%)

SELECTED HONOURS

- 2019, Hastie Prize in Philosophy, the University of Melbourne
- 2016, Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, Monash University